Guide to the John Lewis Gaddis Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
John Lewis Gaddis Papers
1985-2012
MS 2092
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
1.9
(4 boxes)
The collection contains the personal papers of John Lewis Gaddis.
Gaddis, John Lewis, 1941-
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of John Lewis Gaddis, 2018
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collection is restricted until 1 January 2050 by donor request.
Original born digital files, as well as preservation masters, may not be accessed due to their fragility. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist request that they be made. Born digital files cannot be accessed remotely. System requirements include a Manuscripts and Archives computer and file viewing software.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains the personal diaries of John Lewis Gaddis. Subjects include his academic and publishing activities, events in his personal life, his transition to Yale University from Ohio University in the late 1990s, and the founding of the Brady-Johnson Program in Grand Strategy at Yale University. The majority of the diairy entries are typed; some are handwritten.
Arrangement
The material is arranged chronologically.
Biographical / Historical
John Lewis Gaddis was born in Cotulla, Texas in 1941. Gaddis received his B.A., M.A., and Ph.D. from the University of Texas, Austin in 1963, 1965, and 1968, respectively. After earning his Ph.D., Gaddis taught history at Ohio University for 28 years. In 1997, Gaddis became the Robert A. Lovett Professor of Military and Naval History at Yale University. His primary areas of scholarly research and teaching are the Cold War and grand strategy, subjects on which he has authored multiple books. His biography of United States diplomat George F. Kennan, George F. Kennan: An American Life, won the 2012 Pulitzer Prize for Biography or Autobiography.
Cold War; International relations -- Study and teaching; Grand strategy and statecraft; Historians -- United States -- 20th Century; Yale University -- Students; Yale University -- Faculty; Gaddis, John Lewis
- Diaries, 1985-2012
  - 1985-1991 (Box 1, Folder 1-7)
  - 1992-2000 (Box 2, Folder 1-9)
  - 2001-2012 (Box 3, Folder 1-12)
  - Digital copies of diaries, 1988-1998; 7
    Conditions Governing Access
    Original born digital files, as well as preservation masters, may not be accessed due to their fragility. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist request that they be made. Born digital files cannot be accessed remotely. System requirements include a Manuscripts and Archives computer and file viewing software.
    - Backup record, 1988; 1 (Box 4)
    - Backup record, 1989; 1 (Box 4)
    - Backup record, 1991; 1 (Box 4)
    - Backup record, 1992-1993; 1 (Box 4)
    - Backup record, 1996; 1 (Box 4)
    - Backup record, 1997; 1 (Box 4)
    - Backup record, 1998; 1 (Box 4)